You've seen how helpful it could be to import your own modules.
你已经知道导入自己的模块很实用
But what if I told you there was
但是如果我告诉你
an entire library of built-in modules that just come with Python?
有一个包含内置 Python 模块的完整库呢？
This is the Python standard library.
这是 Python 标准库
Up here, you see built-in objects we use throughout this course;
你可以在顶部看到我们在这门课程中用到的内置对象
like built-in functions, data types, and exceptions.
例如内置函数 数据类型和异常
Below that though, are tons of useful modules that you can import.
下面是你可以导入的大量实用模块
Think of this library as a very big set of
可以将这个库看做一个非常庞大的工具集
tools that you can use to help you program in Python.
可以帮助你用 Python 编程
It provides new types of objects and
它提供了新的对象和函数
functions for a range of common and specialized tasks.
可以完成一系列常见和特殊任务
Other people have already written
其他人已经编写了这些代码
this code and put it into useful modules for you to use.
并将这些代码放入实用模块中供你使用
Using modules from the Python standard library to
使用 Python 标准库中的模块
easily access and use existing code gives you a lot of programming power.
轻松地获取和使用现有代码大大增强了你的编程技能
The Python standard library is organized into modules.
Python 标准库按模块整理
Many modules are simply Python files,
很多模块都是简单的 Python 文件
like the Python scripts you've already written and imported.
和你已经编写和导入的 Python 脚本差不多
Let's import this math module.
我们来导入这个 math 模块
Again, an import statement runs the code in the module.
同样 导入语句会运行该模块中的代码
Modules typically contain a lot of definitions and usually don't show any output.
模块通常包含大量定义并且不会显示任何输出
Running the code will make
运行该代码将使你能够使用
all the modules' functions and types of objects available to use.
所有的模块函数和各种对象
Math has a factorial function,
math 有一个 factorial() 函数
which finds the product of a number and all the positive integers less than it.
它可以算出所有小于等于该数字的正整数的积
Four times three, times two,
4 乘以 3 乘以 2 乘以 1
times one is 24,
等于 24
so math.factorial(4) for prints 24.
因此 math.factorial(4) 输出 24
The Python standard library has good documentation for each of its modules,
Python 标准库详细介绍了每种模块
and it's a good idea to read the relevant page whenever you use one.
在使用每个模块时 建议阅读相关的页面
Here's a documentation for the math module.
这是 math 模块的文档
So far, you've seen only one module in the Python standard library.
到目前为止 你只查看了 Python 标准库中的一个模块
It's a good one, but there are many more.
这个模块很有用 但是还有很多其他模块
If you look at the documentation for the whole of the Python standard library,
查看 Python 标准库的整个文档后会发现
modules are listed in groups based on their uses.
模块按照用途分类
Clicking on a name takes you to the documentation for that module,
点击名称会转到该模块的文档页面
which often includes example code that you should feel free to test out.
通常包含一些示例代码 你可以随意测试这些代码